Takaaki FUKAI

7-1-26 Minatojima-minami-machi, Chuo-ku, Kobe, Hyogo 650-0047, Japan ☎ +81-78-940-5555 ⊠ takaaki.fukai@riken.jp

Summary

I received my Ph.D. from the department of computer science, University of Tsukuba in 2018, after obtaining a B.Eng. from Okayama University in 2013. Since January 2020, I have been postdoctoral research at RIKEN Center of Computational Science. Before that, I worked for IBM Japan as a software developer. My research interest centers on how to improve serviceability and security of computer systems without OS-modification and virtualization overhead, by exploiting thin-hypervisor. One of my important works is that I proposed a live migration scheme that works without OS modification and device virtualization.

Affiliation

- Postdoctral researcher in High Performance Big Data Research Team, RIKEN Center of Computational Science (R-CCS)
- Visited Researcher at Information Technology Center, The University of Tokyo

Research and Work Experience

- January 2020-Current: Postdoctral researcher
 High Performance Big Data Research Team RIKEN Center of Computational Science
 I am engaged in research about high-performance computing with next-generation hardware.
- June 2019-Current: Visited Researcher
 Information Technology Center, The University of Tokyo
 I am engaged in research about VMM live refreshing with on-demand nested virtualization [4].
- April 2018-December 2019: Software Developer IBM Japan

I was engaged in the development of a web application, a SaaS cloud service, and a private cloud production.

Education

- September 2018: Doctor of Philosophy in Engineering, University of Tsukuba Supervisor: Professor Kazuhiko Kato
- March 2015: Master of Engineering, University of Tsukuba Supervisor: Professor Kazuhiko Kato
- March 2013: Bachelor of Engineering, Okayama University Supervisor: Professor Hideo Taniguchi

Award

• IEEE Computer Society Japan Chapter Young Author Award 2019.

IEEE Computer Society Tokyo/Japan Joint Chapter, December 2019.

• Best Paper Award.

The 10th IEEE International Conference on Cloud Computing Technology and Science, December 2018.

• Best Paper Award.

The 8th IEEE/ACM International Conference on Utility and Cloud Computing, December 2015.

Publications

Journal Paper

[1] Takaaki Fukai, Takahiro Shinagawa, Kazuhiko Kato.

Live Migration in Bare-metal Clouds.

IEEE Transactions on Cloud Computing, Jul 2018.

(Open Access: https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/8401692)

International Conference/Workshop Papers (Refereed)

[2] Takaaki Fukai, Satoru Takekoshi, Kohei Azuma, Takahiro Shinagawa and Kazuhiko Kato.

BMCArmor: A Hardware Protection Scheme for Bare-Metal Clouds.

In Proceedings of the 9th IEEE International Conference on Cloud Computing Technology and Science (CloudCom 2017), Dec 2017.

[3] Takaaki Fukai, Yushi Omote, Takahiro Shinagawa, and Kazuhiko Kato.

OS-Independent Live Migration Scheme for Bare-metal Clouds.

In Proceedings of the 8th IEEE/ACM International Conference on Utility and Cloud Computing (UCC 2015), Dec 2015.

[Best paper award].

International Conference/Workshop Posters (Refereed)

[4] Ryosuke Yasuoka, Takaaki Fukai and Takahiro Shinagawa.

Toward On-demand Nested Virtualization for Live-Refreshing Cloud Systems.

The Fifteenth EuroSys Conference 2020 (EuroSys '20), poster, April, 2020 (To be appear).

[5] Takaaki Fukai, Yushi Omote, Takahiro Shinagawa, and Kazuhiko Kato.

Live Migration of Bare-metal Instances.

5th Asia-Pacific Workshop on Systems (APSys 2014), June, 2014

Other publications

[6] Masanori Misono, Masahiro Ogino, Takaaki Fukai, Takahiro Shinagawa.

FaultVisor2: Testing Hypervisor Device Drivers against Real Hardware Failures. In Proceedings of the 10th IEEE International Conference on Cloud Computing Technology and Science (CloudCom 2018), Dec 2018.

(Acceptance Ratio: 19.8%) [Best paper award].

- [7] Iori Yoneji, <u>Takaaki Fukai</u>, <u>Takahiro Shinagawa and Kazuhiko Kato</u>. <u>Unified Hardware Abstraction Layer with Device Masquerade</u>. In Proceedings of the 33rd ACM Symposium On Applied Computing (ACM SAC 2018), Apr 2018.
- [8] Ilias Avramidis, Michael Mackay, Posco Tso, <u>Takaaki Fukai</u>, Takahiro Shinagawa. Live Migration on ARM-based Micro-datacentres. In Proceedings of the 3rd Workshop on Edge Computing (EdgeCom 2018), Jan 2018.

Skills

- Research Expertise
 - Thin-hypervisor, Virtualization, Operating systems, Firmware security, IaaS Clouds
- Technical Expertise
 Intel VT-x, PC-architecture low-level programming, Device driver, Linux kernel, QEMU/KVM
- Software service development skills (Technical experience as software developer) Docker, Kubernetes, CI/CD, Microservice architecture, Software test
- Software Programming Skills
 C language(10+ years), x86 assembly, Shell script, Python, Java (Include Android application),
 TypeScript
- Platforms
 Linux, Mac, Windows
- Languages
 Japanese(Native), English(Intermediate)

Research Activities

April 2020-Current Editorial Board Member of IPSJ Transactions on Advanced Computing Systems (ACS)

April 2020-Current Steering Committee Member of IPSJ Special Interest Group on System Software and Operating Systems (SIGOS)

Other Information

Profile page https://fukai-t.github.io/profile-page/

ResearchGate https://www.researchgate.net/profile/Takaaki_Fukai

Linkedin https://www.linkedin.com/in/takaaki-fukai-b378a7141/